...thank you for thank you all for coming to the because session...checkered annual I am
...to program manager with the hyper scale compute team.
Imagine so then the session ...going over
...the...capabilities of service fabric in terms of
managing your services a...services...
Configurations so forth so in this new world as a developer you have multiple
had to
wear one of those things which is a norman this point is your service has to be up
...this five-days-a-year and in...in that in that
duration you also awfully have to add new features but also
have to make sure that you are you have the ability to deploy
newm deploy new features monitor troubleshooting diagnose fix rios
fix issues in real-time you cannot afford a.
Downtime at all so the architecture
...in place the first-time you have...deploying
to introduction has to be working and should meet the needs of even
after five years and that actually is the key thing which will help you do?
So, let me first give you a quick overview of the platform so I'll keep it brief since
I'm sure most of you guys are...mobile sessions architecture talk on
this service fabric and also ...session which visual
on lake on the other room about the service of the programming model so I'll just
quickly go into what this particular big big-picture is out here.
The microsoft sourced fabric has been a key ingredient in taking all of
a tier one box products like sequel link and other like
...transforming them into running as cloud services.
Micro service
...a proven distribute platform that makes it easy to build.
Scalable and reliable services allows you to keep
compute ad associates state together to achieve high throughput
and low latency allows you to manage the full application lifecycle deploys
...monitor trouble shoot and am great applications easily without any downtime.
The call-you develop and test on your and on your
...is the one wichita which deploy onto the cloud...
including the including...private clubs you may have.
For example, in terms of schiel is
...talk about sequel leisure...is one of the largest in the complex users of this application
lifecycle management features of the service fabric the
regularly kick-off close to forty thousand application of...in each of
the clusters worldwide and the platform handles this without any issues.
So, you're getting at platform that is
...for it seems on a daily basis so anyway that's the big introduction
to the platform that's...into the management an application lifecycle capabilities.
So, one of those things which...may have been so in back of the mind is what are the
challenges for managing distributed applications that scale.
Actually I remember reading everything is study which said.
On average a single downtime.
For an hour costs around three hundred
thousand dollars so of course no, customer wants to take that kind of
hit so you absolutely need some reliable optics ensure
Of your application so that,
you know, if there is some partitions running hot all...these need to skill my application up
or skill the environment node...said that say,
for example,
how many times its happen that you will...just add some capacity to your environment?
So, you would opts of course like to have a have a have a platform which is does
it for you so that is actually service fabric.
And, while the platform is doing some of some of the scale...why doesn't it
also do some of the self healing and repairs based on some policies that say, for example,
you could say
if my application service comes down for some reason just restarted...on
the don't make me up but if it's recital doesn't come back then there is a to help threshold
...admitted ok then life is good don't call me but if it really becomes a crisis then of
course call me I'm always available battery and the other thing which is interesting is I don't know-how many
people have taken production support call when you're invocation and just to just
to figure just to just find out that all there was a false alarm value
of distribute family you've done all those things and just to get a false alarm on something so you don't want
...happen so the key would be?
A key would be that you want to have...want to have a system which actually
will accurately describe to you what's going on in the clusters...it is not
...thing has to be something which...will give a deep insights into application out it's
helped its performance what stresses running.
So, these are the things which the management stack of service fabric provides for you.
So, the other thing what the other thing was interesting here...I
...talking about the tested...of it so.
Think about a scenario where you have now been call into a into a
...sites and incident you figure out what the fixes and then you just want to have
some more guarantees history...right fix and you need that need a platform which actually allows you to
...some scenarios which can happen very regularly and production system public provides you
a disability framework for it which you can plug into and...other thing is the configuration
manager is another one of the big topics rich people keep talking about and, for example,
how is it how...how easy was...deploy of fix confident
...production without being on pins and needles worried if I messed up some configuration
out and...by the right version into the right cluster and those are
the things which actually or are very easy to do in service fabric so let
me know go into some of the details are...of the each of these
but point listed and then I can give you some more some more interesting?
...feature, feature descriptions so before I get into it and,
I'm sure you guys have seen this diagram multiple times by now.
But, this basically this is a is a list is actually a collection of machines and they're
only as reliable as and falter as the individual
units so now let me introduce you to the system fabric cluster.
System of fabrics clusters basically a is
...set of machines which could be physical
...on friend on prim scenarios or virtual in as...or any of
the cloud provider you may have and then stitches and
this is together to form a reliable...a fault...unit
kuala cluster these clusters of course can be as smallest five nodes
do pollens of nodes machine total...of nodes?
...for example, in almost every region they have they have clusters
which use up close to thousands of machine thousands of machines and the other thing which is unique about was
...fabric is that you...setting of...your clustered
...specify the failures the...for example,
you can choose to set of a cluster that spans more than one...datacenter
us than the reason why you would do that is a encase I'm so paranoid that if the
...if one of validate...a does has an impact it a my service not
be affected so, for example, like one of for until services called
a bingproton they actually they have clusters the spanned
three datacenters so only last year one of one of the sets of the
...machines in one of the regions went down and they didn't even see
them feel that it went on because there was no impact...the service so subject just...like
...them over to the other two and then after a while and when they got all these
...so many machines that then that's when the...all?
Apparently...machines in one region went down so...
kudos scenery up is really works so this is the same the same software and will
...in terms of sdk which was like yesterday so I actually go through a little
more detail about how to plan for reproduction...later on in the session?
So, quickly let me also touch on what applications
...service applications made up of course alice service
...supports bobble the creation of
...stateless and stateful microsoft...
So, each of these services of course contains a code.
An associated confirmation to
...service package...the service packet is the one which...to server to
...fabric see the data is my service-type and that actually easily unit of
deployment activation so the how the way to think about this service packages are
they are actually
a you could think in terms of it provides you complete functionality...standalone it
...can actually be deployed independently can start on independently that's how you should think in terms
of service package and then each of these service packages of course
has to be contained in something and that containers goal for us it's got it's one of the
containers is called the as called application package this application
packet is actually the unit of lifetime versioning and isolation.
Let me give you a simplesimple example, for example,
an online ticketing application may contain and inventory management...service and opinion
...service all these three actually can
be independently upgraded can be deployed so these can actually be...packages of their
own so in this particularschematic avant-garde...if you look at one of the
packages hundred mb...other one is to gigs.
The reason iec to be the extreme examples is because a lot of times you don't want to touch
...gig version of
...big application package because for the service package because.
I have problems filling them over...problems making sure that are everything in that
...all I have to fixes small package
...a and that I can I should be able to do that so that is
the unit of deployment activation whereas application packets of is actually
the isolation guarantees...get...the versioning so hopefully those
are two things I want to make sure that you guys remember and will uses don's over and over?
...quickly go through and instantiation of this application
...microsoft voices of a services as the put packages talked about.
Like, for example, you...you have application for which is which is ready to go
and it has to services service types and services
...subgroup figure out from...given
...all these all these instances of this service-type a
...I be and if you look at look at the rates listed now...this particular thing
is if you look at be it has actually make sure that you each of these instances
...do get a unique of fall domain
...the you these this actually is
the key to making sure that you're actually on a reliable reliable placement.
So, there is also the concepts of scaling up and partitioning which I'll
talk about later so let me show you how these are done.
One of the top one other thing which agreements this one basically is
...wanted specifically call out every service instance has a unique name the
needs of application that is actually how you address those instead...
Response service types which...just instantiated.
So, devil.
Moi number inc.
So, in this demo actually I will show you a couple of things whereas before I go in there I sort of make sure I
want to show you a preview into our portal this is a service which I
think gopal mentioned also mark mention...there will be a previous service which will actually be in
...actually request for these things so I'm going to give you a preview to that.
Ok.
So, like all.
Like all...a poodle just good new and
Since I've already pairwise showing a...in
this scenario will show up show up in a little more
prominently but...it's actually preview is just give you a quick audio how
it's going to be so I'm going to set up a cluster so, this is...this is how it will it'll work.
What's going on for this right all right so you select your own
...name it's up to you what you want to do so...just say service.
Fabric demo on stage.
One just because...hopefully doesn't go through for all right so.
So, then actually if you look at look at what's the right below web basically synthesis
...this location divest us actually you get a rescues address if you change
...to...us...you get so...a dotting new in terms of service fabric itself is
actually property of the off the portal and
...site itself so...create a new resource group since...am one of those people
...all these names...the same thing.
So,...russ actually talk about resource group I don't know-how many people...this basically any
...social create has to be resource group
actually allows you to thanks at least for this for me it's a good way to see...what
did take to create this cluster so I'll show you what...resource group will end up containing
...you just...in terms of basically I created this service group now and
then the subscription suppose has all subscriptions which you which you haveaccess to.
Location of course today at least for the for this trial run we actually
...liam for regions and m which is vests use at this point then...where actually you
...make some decisions some decisions basically is what kind of
...m do you want this particular cluster to have so in this scenario
...just going to say okay I'll need
...of these lms the you actually choose any number I just have...ten fifteen
fifty actually choose one-two-three-four fire so forth so anything about five is the right number...
So, the name of name of the...you can just say this is the
...stage.
So, this particular prefix actually all dvs used for is name each of the m so we actually
generate names by the one thing which you have to enter for a since
is actually built this service fabric is built on will be
...inside I svm you actually have to give some.
...you are choose a.
Username...password this actually is for our dipping into the into the cluster into the
into the ibm's...
Ok.
So, at this point and basically.
There's a couple more options ok so.
You of course if it's if it's something which your which if...a cluster which
...using for your development purposes most likely you don't want to be secure
and it's easier but is a person plus...want to
...and I and I always suggest that even if it's a development clustered
it's always good to security because you don't want to be das by someone else
...do it so we allow you what is options one.
So, basically, basically can choose to say might have...security the other one is you can actually
give us certificate and then it'll look selective vessel...options
in here talking about okay whatvery reckoned find this certificate so this so
...you should have provision into the key management store already so you just giving the url of the
key one source and that's outcomes so anyway so for this purpose is I just make it make it the
...secure and this go on.
Can create?
So, it's great it's so since it's...like...fire-fighting minutes
...going to go and...take cluster which I already have.
The...clusters.
Let me take this one this actually is the cluster which I want to use
...demos today so if you look at.
In this blade basically couple of things which are interesting here in terms of essential
...which you which you have.
So, this basically...here is actually your collect ip address which would use
the...initial used to connect to this cluster and then here there are
some of the few other things here load monitor
...actually just gives you real-time as to what's going on with your
...and we have actually three states which are more and more interesting so
for node you...you either...node is
...or it could be get everything is good it's reacting rel...unknown,
unknown comes and only if...if
we just barely join and we don't know it state and then warning is when something is really
going on so basically that's the health state directly from the system.
...application actually here I have deployed to applications in it
so just says that there are two of them okay and then there are not and warning so I'll
quickly go into the into the reason why I...split this into the different states
most of them are not if it's okay you actually have no real reason to go in and see if
...notice okay because we should respect the system but in the scenarios go in and say okay
here's a here's a here's a cluster of nine nodes and I have
a and all of them are okay and then if you look at basically we of
...strived across safety's and you these combination so there are
three of these and then there are five a great domains.
And,...actually go through if you have the time we actually can talk about
the domain concept a little bit later so basically this is used
...your upgrading your applications that's the that's when...domains
...used all right so then let's go into quickly into a few more things which are which we just
talked about so application margin that...applications I have in here so let's just look at the.
One of these.
So, in this...says that health...okay and.
And, here's a version of these applications.
This is that the address of the application and the in this is where
...the name space under which the rest of the services will be will be under
and in this particular particular application...there
are services and there are two services...them the one of them is.
Is a...little bit one of them is
...stateful one as a stateless one and then so the key here is now what event
...from a from the cluster you went
...applications and applications down to services and here is now
...actually let's go into a stateful application...you look at so that actually go
into it actually gets into?
How many partitions it has and then if you go to the partition that's when you see this
...running a single partition and it's healthy
...state now if you step back and think about the report
help them different levels one of the class level are used at the application-level
...the service level...the partition level at...
level we actually do all the way all the way down and then each of these are well-defined in terms of health
...can how...errors warning and then there'sthere's of unknown just because there
maybe scenarios where
...systems system itself is waiting for ...to come up and that's very rare state
to happen so it's still there and what's interesting about all these things all these
...health framework is we'll talk about more will help
...but is that you can also report help if you actually have
...you if you have an external service which actually is going to report help on behalf of your
application you can you can still use that uses framework...and this will also open the
...so, anyway, so, that?
So, now that we have seen this let me-let me now do one thing...I
...also introduce you to this
particular tool which actually you can use till you have access to the
...of course comes in only probably until then this is the tool which we have
...as a part of sdk so in this particular cluster?
Is here so not this one this was when I was playing with
so this one basically has the chaos does app
...minor to the things you just saw it has...is
...versioning as well so we just for this demo...I'll do is let me just?
Bring up one of the
one ofthe applications I have here is actually use the application which has
...bouncing pyramids which I'm sure...the other demos so now I'm...get into the details
of what each of these how do you define it in terms of management of the versioning
redefine...application to service fabric
so application type itself is defined by the application...
In this manifest in this thing actually I have to
...services one of them is...stateful visual object service package another...objects
Each of them have a version of.
What...washroom one?
And, then.
Basically says is the services are
...version one and then it says that application is also version one
okay and then very you define these two so this would be defining this service
...so for each of...service types you actually have a
manifests which actually describes that for you so each of
these have a code which has which is the version one and then...a
...can't think of version one and then we also then in turn.
Also...the service manifests which actually is referred to in the application manifests look at the
with here the and the service fabric itself does not care about
what scheme you use you can actually squalid version aviation be
...c doesn't matter so...makes sense to you lot-of...even call it
okay this is the version number like total and seventeen
dot something because that's how it makes sense for them so that's there's no wishing...just basically,
basically string and all we care about is when you go to deploy it and,
then a braided later we just...make sure that this actually is different from what what's already running
as long as you are making sure that you have a way of methodology...and...go
with it in this scenario is taken this for part wishing scheme that's...it is.
All right so visual...I'm sort of.
They will solution that's going to be here quickly.
...that is packaged so I have to options, you know,
one silicon connector may cluster from here from visual studio and then deployed so
that...that portion of it was a talk which you like it was last...you guys...land and
...talk about so I'm re-use partial because that's since to be the operational
tomost of the most of the time you'll be using that once you once you have stuff and production so let me just
use that so a couple of things which is very interesting so very first thing which you which...
this scenario is like you have to define you have to copy this packages created.
Created into the...store which is...running of
...so I already copied once and certainly when I agree I...I show you a blade...
certainly copy the so just for the sake of time I was copied now so then the next thing you do is
telecast...the cluster that yes I have actually a new application type.
And, then all you're doing is instantiate one copy of this.
And, that's new so if you now look at look at...should be running this.
Look, at
...is actually there you see widget visual objects application
...says yes I understand these things and now you would see that is actually deployed.
And, I have actually...and these are these are actually has have nine partitions...since I
said that actually has to be on all the machines and that's what happened
so let's look at look at the output of this per secondbecause that's going to be the...award.
So,...can see it relevant.
And, what's going on here.
All right so amazing...on another one here.
Okay, so, we now have...filaments so let's do a
quick upgrade and that actually or maybe it's all okay let's come to the
grid later so let's go back to my the rest of the stuff which I want to talk about.
All right so then the other thing other concept which I want also talk about...the ability
for you to make sure you can...a single...package in this scenario what I would do is
basically upgrade a grid esri one of the service
packages I have so in this particular schematic I have here I'm just going a
...the yellow, yellow hexagons with the green ones
and then basically this is basically the system takes care of
...it one you...time is actually walk through basically what happens is
...updates progresses from one-at-a-time...sequence actually is chosen by
system fabric so you don't get...which you...go first but the
...done by system fabric but it always do what you...so that you don't lose any availability?
The...xr also performed at the beginning of these upgrade and then
add up end of each...the so that if they have...are not met the
...either rollback automatically or is...the application developer can
and debug the...and then the one of the via
booster for the application developer can then either restart doubly saying that okay
I think it was a false alarm...is go on...or...system
too to rollback or role forward so...those three are the options you
...breed you can...forward or just rollback?
At any no-point is the service
...be lost so the question I'm sure people are you guys are thinking about
...what kind of help policies can define the to levels you can defines...that one
of the class level you can say that of the nine machines I've got as long as...
doesn't impact more than two or I'm okay so you can say okay ten percent of my
nodes or twenty percent of nodes can be down it's all...there's no need to rollback but
...also specify that application you don't want to lose availability offered at all so
...none of my applications...availability if it does then you just
have a policy can choose to say I do you do now...role forward or
...so these are things which can do so let me show you this an action.
...so number.
So, I'm back here.
So, what I'm going to do very simply is?
I'll go to go to my
stateful objects actor dot cs which is actually...one of my.
It's actually in one of my service packages here
it's actually in this analysis...just make a small change here
...vacancy...mechanistic...a little bit.
...make just make the moment to be true so that's basically all it does is.
The payments rotate that's all it does so I'm going to use visual studio to compile it.
And, then package...package.
Once packaged...I can deploy from here but I...to go through
a like I want to show you specifically what are the few things which you actually have a
can for in this...scenario only the only.
Thing which we change was one of one of the packages so let's go to that go to the package at
this point is release so since you see the see the...actually generated
two of them so we suddenly not machines this guy so I'm going to remove that packages the
remove that so
here's this is the one which I change so I just go in I edits in my service manifests.
And, then I'm all I'm going to do is make
...changes so this version number two and then I
see okay I m going I...change the code a little bit and then
I'm also going to chains associated conflict for it and then just...back.
And, then you go back and then define the same thing same thing in...application manifest.
So, that now...the to the system that yes I actually
machines this visual object service package to version number two.
I did not change the visual objects...the web package are not...it's...just fine.
And, then I just change the application version here.
That's it and the save it.
And, then the next thing which you do what the partial.
...copy...mario copying that package into...
So, it says that it's copied.
...register this new one.
So, once you register...is go back to quickly to this thing and say
...saw there were actually this one version of application sitting in there this is the view to
your emit store so let me quickly.
Refreshed.
...me go back to the application here.
And, you see there is actually now a second,
second version of your application registered in this very clearly the only one of the
packages has changed the second one has not changed so the system itself now understands that it doesn't need
...visual objects web service that all the only thing is going to
...the stateful visual...social...one.
So, now let's quickly go and initiate the they're great they're great.
Someone this is that this is the partial command starts...service rogue
application run it and then you can actually go back and we also
bring my.
By this thing here.
So,...celebrating so shortly
...see...like...this blue one basically sort...
And, then let me just do...fresh air.
So, as progress...you can actually see it to...here.
So, basically what you're what you're saying is the is that each one of them slowly
...starts to as though you these progress as the
...progress is through the grid domains each of these little
bouncing pyramid starts to have rotation...in them?
And, now it says that is completed...these so should have at least two of them which
of which is now...of them have rotations insert in addition to.
So, I let this go...let me just go on to a and we'll come back to this.
So, here's an interesting one so now that you have an application I showed you that it can be it can be a
grated so, I want-to talk to-you about what are all the all
the key aspects which are features which are built into...fabric that will help you
deploy your application into production with conference one security
...a very big thing for...I and in
fact microsoft so it's even bigger deal so security was build-up built
ground-up from the...into the platform we support...access control the you can use certificates
to secure application and the cluster all the system logs and events
...blog application logs and traces are retained per the customer policies
...so...something which you can say okay I need to have seven weeks of
often logs and that's what what's what you can actually choose to indicate
jon system and that's what we'll that's what you would keep?
Application scale-up so when you're a small
start-up or testing the market out.
There is...strongly to be are able to offer the service with minimal
expense but the ability to scaled if needed so...
there's no telling as to when you have a spike in the need and that's when you want
to go and deploy...new set of applications...point I'll service...allows you to just do that
...allowing you to partition your application you can choose a very large portion
as plus-minus in sixty-four partitions and deploy to a small cluster and that's
...so you'll bing only if only for the expenses
...that particular cluster right so that actually would mean that your clogs are lower to
...and then as the demand increases you can actually say
okay verifiable increase it to whatever it needs to be maybe go from nine to say
...so that's exactly what can what can happen?
So, then the next topic would be application reliability so,
what kind of...failures do-you want-to survive what's your isolate how many replicas
does your service and these other questions you need to ask about when...you when you think in terms of?
...think in terms of reliability which you need...also think in terms of okay do I
want to survive like an added datacenter going on so those are the
think times when you spanned added datacenters so these are the
...you have ask yourself and the system fabric of course allows you do not
...think about these things but also make sure that...implemented the rightly and then
...us...more things will be a disability services that actually is a is a
service which actually allows you to test your applications width
real-life scenarios which can happen in production no
one wants addresses test the limits of...this service and production supreme
...customers customer data all your sat with them at risk so this
...service can be used assimilate simulate
...available scenarios which may happen in...time...in terms of ours.
all you need to do is simply, simply enable this particular service in your
...cluster and then basically it will do it'll put the application your application to
spaces synthesis...this
...also integrator where they are with your health system it'll pauses test if the application
fields so this is very important so...as soon as the application has a
...pauses so you can attaching debug and fix the issue and then you get to restart applications
the possibly service at that point.
So, then the let me go on to the last topic which is actually the ...marketing and diagnostics and that
...actually uncover offer the demo I can let me just give you
a demo off of this that the disability services.
I want to introduce you to a this cluster monitor which we have which I'm sure
you've...seen this before.
So, now I have.
I have a nice ui out here
which is which indicates the nine nodes which I have here?
And, then I have a lot of applications apply...
So, I just wanted-to talk to-you about a couple of things so we have not talked about
Let me show you a couple of interesting things here
in terms of reliability what does it what does it give you so let me take just this particular
satisfy the service fabric explorer and then just kill often node.
Say, for example, let me just take this.
...one five suffice seven.
So, you would see something very interesting in here so to...
And, it's...asking can restart.
So, when do it so you would see that does?
The system fabric actually moved all those replicas office offers into something else so basically
there's actually simulating a scenario where you actually lost
in a particular known in production.
And, then when it comes back?
...services that...replicas and...back so that's...that's.
See that...
Ok,
so, this is something which of course you can sit on also...and try to do this once in awhile and
directories not very scalable so...let's see if began.
Let me just bring up my in...services...me a second.
All right I'd say to nowhere.
So, anyway, so,...the lack of time actually...one and
...show you guys the disability service some of the time it gets.
So, let me...back.
So, what...this point is basically?
Service...a...what containers...service...allows you to specify rules
of on placement resource balancing...resource consumption is
not capacity and...them...real...hedges these on a
on running cluster and the system and manage resources resource balancing for you,
for example,
for example,...uses this...basically they offer three kinds of databases say, for example,
and, they have standard free in...premium
...capacity such that the premium database reports its load as that...that the
...of the whole complete machine so then what happens is since
the premium database is already taken up the whole machine...we this...fabric actually knows that
...place any of the free skews out there so these rules are expected
even...performing the...application of great or rollback?
So, let me quickly show you.
How easy it is the for you to define?
Define the...capacity and, reports...loads.
So, I have an application out here so this particular this then and this.
There is a manifests...the plus manifest actually nothing it's nothing but
which defines the cluster which...just deployed and
then in this in this basically the to there is in each of these no types...the vm
...see...the capacity of the vm is just this...you just add this particular segment
...then the system knows here's a capacity for that.
And, then add and from your service all you're doing is you just have
...make a call.
And, this report the load and based on the load system react reactivated and figure out
...particular one is taking up of...of the
...and then it'll react to it and make sure that
...it...indifference conservation how much of the capacity of this one this one just
talks about hundred so it can place only five of them in there so if it hits more
...if there is a six-one then basically and it actually will deport that either there's no
...or it will this place it in a...which has
...space so it's very easy for you to report load of from an application.
All right now let's just go into the topic the very last topic which I had I
talked about is monitoring your services while running you're running your service
in productions critical that you have visibility and your application sort of what services what your
application and services are doing and I...categorize them into three one is
performance stress response service alta status collection of elementary dataon
your service microsoft so subscribe enables you to do all of these with these.
For performance monitoring the emit detailed platform metrics for both the
program models the program models which mark and, ripple talked about what for both of them we actually
in emit and detailed.
...platform metrics you can combine them with your own custom metrics to
understand as to how we are application is handling spikes and surges of
custom load figure out what's the lowest the slowest
...calls and also...and, those things you can use...
So, are maybe...understand what the...a data...load?
Since we emit standard dw events you can use any tool of which you want which
of your choice and then you can visualize this?
And, the second topic was what was the health status monitoring for help-wanted
...build a flexible and extensible
...store that provides reports of reports of helpful the cluster
the applications the system services running...it and you can easily ad records for
...services you right you can check the health
...reports on the portal which I just showed you in the service fabric that's the other thing and the service
web...some the other tool which is also...for you and sdk.
And, then you can certainly
plumb this into any other any other tool of your choices you many.
The platform uses this health store for many of
...actions including monitor application...and,
basically it actuallyuses that to safely rollback of
as a new version of application which is destabilizing your production
...the last one which is also a part of your
...actually the business telemetry in this day and age
of data-driven decision-making we enable you to collect...
drive-in sites from your customer interaction your application and
...let me quickly show you an example of how you can use app insights to
surface the system generated counters along with any system any of the
custom counters you may have created in your in your application.
That's...look at.
I have I have actually a.
One of the app insights already treated out here.
...favorite crazier...on.
Okay, there you are so...demo...
So, if you would see something which is interesting out here.
So, what does give you...basically a is list of the...system generated,
generated counters so there's basically says that's all the number of
...actors I have theme in this...lackluster ...the over the past twenty four
...for two-point-five speakeasy the number of a
eisenhower of it is the number of facing calls the get...is the set?
So, all the key here is you can actually have your own custom metrics or you can actually,
actually look at look, at the look at the ones which system generates
for you and then of course use all the powers of app
...to make sense of what is going on with...application.
All right so let's look at the look at the one more interesting things we talked about
monitoring we talked about health now it's interesting to see what are the all
...order one of the tools which...systems sorry service fabric provides
you for diagnoses and, troubleshooting
...broken them into three buckets because of that is the easier way for me to understand this or details
...mopix this actually allows you to know what service...was doing at the time of incident
...latest typically it's very helpful the helpful for you to know what the system,
system was doing so that you actually do the system as an issue of
...bambi more focused on what exactly happened at that point based
on the system movement and the application thing so, for example,
the system operates include all...of important system events such as applications
...applicants service deployment the upgrades the...creation save
...loads...calls or exploiting cancellations run icing
calls better failing so forth?
The second piece of it is the second bucket which I have
...a custom application training this is the only way for you to make sure that you can extend
...functionality which is which service fabric provides you
out-of-the-box so you can combine your own application traces with the system traces together
holistic address signing for you to troubleshooting problem and
...use each w so...custom tracing code...added in the on
local one box actually works exactly the same way when you when you
deploy into the cloud so you don't have to related you can certainly use any tool of your choice visualize the
street these traces I'm sure people like bonneville you like lashes search
you can use a operational insights...or...the
via is diagnostics even viewer which actually is a part of a sticky which you get?
So, in the program we'll talk I'm suremark and...actually use the visual studio diagnosis even
...you are by pressing a fly so I will not show you that I'll
just show you how these can be done in the...operational insights?
Okay, so, let...get too so I don't know-how many how many folks have actually played with operation
...so I will not actually get into the details of what
a operation insights itself is because that's another talk by itself so
they just go through very quickly I want to understand I've known make sure that
I've actually routed all my all my traces and all the
all the evens which I have over the course of some time into a next-door
...and then basically option insights actually is the one which I'm using to create
...let me find
outbasically give me all the system events that the notifying that an application that we...started.
So, like you say...here is and then just says ...in
...on a on sunday twenty-six there was something which happened and then if you just look
at actually will tell you that yes there was something which happened there and it was...
Give-me all the events which for which the
...application was created and here's a here's the complete list for it so this
one what I'm trying to steiner indicate here is the searches you create
...something which you can leverage using the keywords which we ve will
...okay you can actually search for created application created application of
...started application...deleted the application of...and
...completed so forth so that's about the thing I want to show you in terms of
...the option sites.
So, this actually can be used for figuring out what actually exactly...your cluster.
Ok, let's go back to my powerpoint...quickly.
...three minutes okay so they must
...actually is a high-level workflow of...does
...truly work in a descrip
...form which has which has like hundreds of
...there's certainly you can't actually expect expect all
events to flow of one of the time so you actually we allow you to
use of windows agile diagnostics and that actually intern bumped into
...people and then opt...that's exactly what...use...example office mopix of course
...includes the like...load calls so forth.
All right so now we come to the
enough my talk so I'm just going to recap as to what we just talk about subscribe
management capabilities of that'll enable...the services,
services your services without downtime twenty-four seventies five-days-a-year
so subject can manage clusters small and large.
Handle failures machines or applications automatically and is an
effected by hardware software communication failures makes application lifecycle easy
supports automated monitored uprolling upgrades with tool back since actually is
...store?
It gives you a container...automatic
...balancing governance based on rules and shows efficiency,
efficiency performance scale density resulting in better
...and provides extensible help diagnostics and marking edges
...just showed you those.
I've come to the end of my talk thank you for listening and I have something for you just try that
...key today media feedback thank you very much.